嘿 Renaldo
Yo, Renaldo!
- Renaldo - 干嘛
- Renaldo! - Que?
下次你把麦圈吃完了 跟我说一声
Next time you finish up the box, you need to holler on it, yo.
知道了 知道了
See,see
妈妈咪呀
Your mami ya
伙计们 是Omar
Hey, y'all, it's Omar.
Omar来了
Omar.
- 他在那 - Omar走来了
- There he is. - Omar step, yo.
Omar来了
Omar, yo.
没蜂蜜杏仁味的了?
Y'all ain't got no Honey Nut?
就你看到那些了
Whatever you see.
来包纽堡烟
And a carton of Newports.
Omar来了
Omar comin'.
嘿 他来了
Hey, y'all, here he come.
Omar来了
Omar. Omar.
Omar在溜达呢
Omar strollin'.
他们没蜂蜜杏仁味的?
They don't have the Honey Nut?
我甚至都不想要这个 老弟
I don't even want this, dawg.
为什么
Why not?
关键不是拿了什么 关键是从谁那里拿的 明白?
It ain't what you're taking,  it's who you taking it from, you feel me?
要是整天尽在逗弄小狗
How you expect to run with  the wolve-s come night
晚上怎么和群狼奔跑?
when you spend all day  sporting with the puppies?
火线重案组 第四季 第3集
the.wire.s04e03
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
"我真爱开学第一天 每个人都真他妈友善"     -Namond Brice
看来你是支持Royce连任了
So you staying with Royce, I see?
什么意思
What you mean?
搞错没
Oh, man.
也难怪 我知道你受够Carcetti了
Makes sense since I know you  got your fill of Carcetti.
他们这阵子老插一堆这玩意儿
They've been puttin' up  a crop of these things
这个街区每个草坪上都插
on every lawn on the block.
我一拿掉
And as fast as I take 'em down,
他们就又插新的
they bring more.
每年这个时候 他们都是这样的
That's what they do this time of year.
貌似你挺清闲嘛
I see you're at your leisure.
我一周值两次夜班
I work two nights a week,
三次日班
three day shifts
周末不休
and no weekends.
下午就没空了
I'm off till this afternoon.
你也不介意?
You're good with it?
比不上在Hopkins大学干 也将就了
It ain't the Hopkins gig, but it'll do.
一年5万2 福利不错
Pullin' 52, good bennies,
配车可作私用
got a take-home car.
虽然宾馆经理是个鸟人 但条件挺不错了
I mean the hotel manager's a pain  in the ass, but still.
如果你有空 我听到个消息 跟你说说
Well, if you was a bit free,  I heard something.
马里兰大学社福学院有个项目
This thing over at University  of Maryland School of Social Work--
有拨款 大把的钱
they got a grant. Big money.
别说了
Just stop.
50万经费 用来研究反复暴力施加者
Half a million to look  at repeat violent offenders,
找临床解决措施之类乱七八糟的
clinical intervention--all that mess.
他们是要做研究咯
So they gonna study some shit, huh?
Melvin 去年我在警局里
Melvin, I had me a good helping  of them downtown,
这种人见多了
tie-wearing, come-to-do-good,
西装革履 一心变革的学者型
stay-to-do-well college types last year.
你确定吗 如果你想要这个活 我已经和那边说好了
You sure? 'Cause I sold 'em on it,  should you want it.
你校园里头可是名头大得很
Bunny, you're a big man down on the campus.
你可是把它贩毒合法化的人
You the police that legalized it.
大学里这些人很欣赏那团乱麻
The college boys loved that mess.
可惜没别人欣赏
Nobody else did, though.
我尽力了
Well, I tried.
是的
You did.
跟黑衣服那几个要 pandemic(一种海洛因)
Yo, blacktops, pandemic.
Pandemic 卖pandemic啦
Pandemic, got that pandemic.
Pandemic
Pandemic.
兄弟 要pandemic吗 找这几个穿黑衣服的
My mac, pandemic, blacktops right here.
就是那个男孩 对吧
That's my boy, right?
不要救济 想自己谋生
Ain't taking no handouts,  but he workin' for it.
知道我什么意思了吧
See what I mean?
这个黑鬼把这个角落搞起来了
This nigga's made a little something  out of this corner.
别急 孩子 现在只是跟他谈谈
Now hold on, son. We're just talking now.
行吗
All right?
你们这个地方搞得不错啊
Man, y'all did good with this spot.
你是个不错的推销员
You a rightful hustler.
你叫什么来着 Boney? Biddy?
What's your name again, man?  Boney? Biddy?
是什么来着
What's it now?
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
是 但事情是这样的
Yeah, but now here's the thing:
这个据点发展起来了 我们要接手
With this spot all built up and shit,  we need it, yo.
Yeah.
什么
What?
两个选择 你现在要不就跟我们拿货 要不就走人
Two choices: You can start  taking our packages or you can step off.
我兄弟Chris到时候会跟你打招呼的
My man Chris is gonna holla at you,  all right?
你再告诉他 你选哪条路
You tell him what it need to be.
不要再等待pandemic了 它就在这里
Don't wait for the pandemic.  It's right here, y'all.
pandemic 现在就买 别再犹豫
Don't sleep on the pandemic.
我想多了解一点那个男孩
I want to know more about  that boy right there.
有潜质
Got good signs on him.
小狗长着大爪子
Big paws on a puppy, huh?
没错 小狗长着大爪子 一点没错
Yeah, big paws on a puppy. To a "T."
摔倒前先找着路面哎
Get that blacktop before you flop.
买点pandemic
Get that pandemic.
事实上 我们不知道他为何被杀害
The truth is we don't know  why he was killed.
可能因为他是目击证人
It could have had something  to do with him being a witness
也可能与此无关
or it could be unrelated.
不管是谁把那破事泄露给Carcetti阵营的
Now, whoever leaked that shit  to Carcetti's camp,
他们骗了我们
they lied on us.
就这样了
Yeah, well, that's it.
涨了8个百分点
Eight points--
Carcetti只能追到这程度了
close as Carcetti gets.
他想搞我
He wants to go big dick with me?
我要给他点颜色看看
I'll show him what he can't handle.
放出风声去
We put it out there:
哪个一脚踏两船的 我下一任期 他就坐冷板凳去
Anyone contributing to both sides  gets frozen out of my next term.
- 不许再有人持观望态度 - 好
- No one rides the middle anymore. - Done.
我要公共服务部和住房社区部
Next, I want DPW and HCD
今天就出动
out there today
把所有Carcetti的标牌都拆掉
tearing down all Carcetti's signs.
所有灯柱 安全岛
Any lamppost, median,
市属大楼 都清理干净 如果房主不出来争辩
any city-owned buildings,  unless the homeowner's out there arguing,
- 都拆了 - 好
- tear it down. - Done.
第三 让交通部
Third, I want transpo
驻扎在Carcetti的总部外头
camped outside of Carcetti's headquarters.
任何车 有任何违章现象 趴活的出租车
Any car, any violation,  the meter flag goes up,
或有贴着车检标志的 都拖走
inspection sticker-- tow it.
好
Done.
接下来 你们俩 拖延事态的发展
Next, you two, slow it down.
初选结束前 那宗谋杀案不许再有任何结论
Nothing else comes out about that murder  until after the primary.
我要你们两个去找媒体
And I want both of you
把证人那个角度轻描淡写地压下去
to go to the press and talk down  that witness angle.
不管媒体反应如何 都把事顶下来
Take the full weight either way it goes.
Clarence 我现在和Bond民调持平
Clarence, I'm running dead even  with Bond right now.
如果我把你踢出配对选举 你还怎么竞选呢
How are you gonna be running  if I drop you from the ticket?
好 就这样吧
Okay, that's it.
先生们 感谢
Thank you, gentlemen.
去做事吧 现在就去
Go to it. Now.
市长先生
- Mr. Mayor. - Mm-hmm.
- 什么事 - Carcetti不是没道理
- What? - Carcetti has a point.
我去了Annapolis
I went down to Annapolis,
为证人保护计划搞到对等资金
got matching funds for witness protection.
你一分钱都没花在实施计划上
You didn't earmark a dime  to put 'em into play.
下个财政年度再说
Next fiscal year.
这事别拿没钱做借口
Don't claim poverty on this.
我们只要25万而已
We're only talking a quarter of a million.
我要是现在申领这笔钱 就给了那个狗日的Carcetti
I match those funds now  and that motherfucker Carcetti,
一个竞选亮点
he's got a campaign high light:
"Tommy Carcetti扩大证人保护计划
"Tommy Carcetti expands witness  protection program.
奋力争取 成功获得额外资金"
Fought for and won extra funds."
去他妈的
Hell with that!
我会在选举以后认领本州拨款
I go after that state-match funds  after the election.
不对 我付了三颗丸子的钱
Naw naw, I paid for three pills.
听着 蓝衣服给两颗
Look, blue shirt gets two.
- 不行 我拿两颗 - 白衣服给一颗
- Naw, I get two.  - White shirt gets one.
- 骗人的狗杂种 - 我拿四颗
- Cheatin' motherfucker.  - I get four.
听好 蓝衣服两颗 白衣服一颗 光膀子一颗
Look, blue shirt gets two,  white one, no shirt one.
花多少钱就拿多少东西 然后走人
Now y'all can take what y'all paid for  and walk away
不然就两手空空地走人 滚你妈的退钱
or just walk away with nothing.  Motherfuck a refund.
没门 黑鬼 我付了三颗的钱
No, nigga, I paid for three.
你再考虑下 敢碰我 会有什么下场
You need to rethink what putting a hand  on me's gonna get you.
谢谢你们这个朋友吧 你们都没得爽了
You can thank your friend here  for snatching away y'all highs.
喂 等等 我可以拿走我那两颗吗
Yo yo, hold up, hold up.  Can I get my two?
就是嘛 就该这么干
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
别跟他们废话
You don't rattle.
你来跟我干 小伙子
Yo, you come up under my wing, young'un,
前途无量啊
you ain't gonna do nothin' but rise, man.
我真不懂你为什么要不干了
I don't even know  why you thinkin' about quittin'.
我跟你说过了
Look, man, like I already told you--
我钱全还清了 而且明天就开学了
I'm all the way repaid,  and tomorrow's school.
得了 你他妈上什么学啊
Come on, man, what the fuck do you want  to go to school for?
你以后想做什么
What do you want to be?
宇航员? 牙医? 律师?
An astronaut? A dentist?  A pay lawyer, nigga?
这样吧
Look, check it out:
你放学以后来这里
Why don't you just come down here  after school
生意最忙的时候帮把手 怎样
and just work these rush hours for me.  How about that:
Hey. Hey.
太好了 谢谢 我知道这么多钱...
That's great. Thank you.  I know that kind of money--
我说 这么多钱 谁都不容易拿
I said I know that kind of money  doesn't come easy to anyone.
不 是我这边有点吵 造房子什么的
No, it's just something on my end here  some construction or something--
好
right.
好的 再次感谢
Yeah, right. Thanks again.
两个小时搞到3万
Two hours, 30 grand.
我这可算是入了门道了吧
Am I getting the hang of this or what?
那他妈怎么回事
What the fuck is that?
公共服务部就在咱门口拆人行道
DPW's tearing up the sidewalk  right outside our door.
你真把他惹毛了
You really pissed him off.
没错 的确这样 不是吗
Yes, I did, didn't l?
走吧 去lrvington社区做上门拉票
Come on. Door-to-door in lrvington.
- 对哦 - 我们今晚忙那个遇害证人的事
- Right.  - And we got that dead witness tonight.
嗯 联邦的人?
Yeah. Federal?
她不是联邦的
Naw, she ain't no federal.
就是本市警察
That there a city girl.
我也喜欢矮个子 她还不错
I like shorty too. She's all right...
只要她别碍我的事
as long as she don't get in my way.
那里是补货源的地方
Re-up right there.
为什么
Por qu?
明天才开学 对吧
School ain't starting till tomorrow, right?
那个小孩穿戴整齐 却没学可上
The little one'll be all dressed up  with nowhere to go.
你也知道的吧 姑娘
Yeah, you know it too, don't you, girl?
有摄像头 如果你从前门入 他们会...
The camera-- if you go in front,  they're gonna--
他们本该知道是我
They're supposed to know it's me, man.
我的风格独此一家 懂没?
I'm my own trademark. You feel me?
懂 但如果他们知道是你 那么...
S? but if they know it's you, then--
怎么 你怕暴露身份?
What, you scared on bein' made, huh?
说什么呐
Claro que s?
不如我给你穿上全套兔子服
How 'bout I put you in one  of them full-body bunny suits?
那看起来就像一只6英尺高的兔子 拿枪指着他们
You'd be like a six-foot rabbit  putting a pistol in their face.
给我一包口香糖
Let me get a pack of Juicy Fruit.
你看着像那种一半灵魂 一半中国血统的人
You look like one of them half-soul,  half-Chinese types
从越南之类地方来的
from Vietnam and shit.
再来哦 妈妈桑
Come again now, Mama-san.
耐心点 姑娘
Patience, girl.
再耐心点
More patience.
那人开一辆破车 经营一个廉价小超市
The guy drives a shit box.  He's got a two-bit minimart,
但超市后门是增强型钢筋
but the back door in there  is reinforced steel,
街上装的保安摄像头很高级
and the security camera  on the street is high-end.
不仅如此 我想我今天还撞见他们补充货源
Not only that, but I think  I made the re-up today:
一个女生 背着个沉甸甸的背包
Schoolgirl with a heavy backpack.
我查了Andre的通话记录
Hmm. Well, I pulled Andre's phone history
想找出Marlo的组织情况
trying to find Marlo's organization,
把他的拨出号码记录跟其他手机号做了比对
cross-referencing DNRs to other cells.
这个是Fruit 这个是Monk
This is Fruit. This is Monk,
这儿还有三四个号码也很有可能是他们的
and there's three  or four other good probables.
这样找很难挖到Marlo的直线号码
Not likely to find a direct line  to Marlo that way.
Andre得通过Monk来跟他说上话
Andre had to go through Monk  to get to him.
是难 但我们可能找到Chris Partlow的号码
No, but we might get a cell  on Chris Partlow,
或者挖出三几个高级副手的号码来
or for tote or for one,  of the top lieutenants.
- 我们就快达成目标了 - 可不
- We're gettin' close.  - Uh-huh.
副总把我叫到市里去了
Deputy pulled me downtown.
你们没惹上什么麻烦吧?
You guys aren't into any shit, are you?
没有 长官
No, sir.
好在今天他没去下海
Good he wasn't down at the ocean today.
传票呢?
And the subpoenas?
初选之前 你一页报告都看不到
You won't see a page of anything  until after the primary.
之后呢 如果有文件出来又没人去看的话
After that, if a document lands  and there's no one there to read it,
市长和他的人会真的在乎么?
will the mayor and his people honestly  give a shit?
除此之外 我只能告诉你
Other than that, what can I tell you
把组里的人召回到街上 他们应该呆的地方去
except to get that unit back  on the street where it belongs?
警官 你不再主管重大犯罪科了
Lieutenant, you are relieved  from command of Major Crimes.
你所做的工作非常出色
You've done exceptional work,
有鉴于此 我们希望你能更上一层楼
and in light of that, we want you  to improve the performance
担当另一项极为重要的任务
of another vital aspect of our mission--
- 长官? - 负责电话报告科
- Sir?  - Telephone Reporting Unit.
你明天一早就去报到 八点整
You report there tomorrow, 0800.
我做错什么了吗
Have I done something wrong?
Marimow警官将接管重案组
Lieutenant Marimow will  be taking over Major Crimes.
如果你需要跟他交接工作 务必尽快完成
If you need to brief him, do so promptly.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
Jimmy 沙滩那个房子怎么样了?
Jimmy, how's that beach house coming?
沙滩 呃 还好啦 长官
Beach... um, fine, sir--
好极了 听起来好极了
Great. Sounds great.
帮我递个漏勺行吗?
Yeah, hand me the colander, will you?
他这么早就到了
He's early.
你去开门 我来弄这个
You get the door. I'll do that.
- 哎 快进来 - 哎
- Hey! Come in. - Hey!
哇 好香啊
Ooh, smells good.
意大利面 没啥高级的 法国红葡萄酒?
Spaghetti-- nothing fancy.
柜台那儿的品酒师说这种是干红
Yeah, the sommelier behind the plexi  said it was dry.
Beadie!
Hey, Beadie!
Bunk 别来无恙
Hey, Bunk, how you doing?
哇 你这整一个金发美女呢
Whoa, look at you! Blonde and all.
- 你喜欢这造型? - 喜欢 喜欢
- You like it?  - I do, I do.
小朋友们
Hey, kids.
他叫Jack 她叫Cary 这位是Moreland警探
This is Jack, that's Cary.  This is Detective Moreland.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi.  - Hi!
叫我Bunk
Call me Bunk.
我来开这瓶酒
Let me open this wine.
没错 得让那鸟玩意儿醒一段时间
Yeah, that's right. Let that shit breathe.
对不起 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
没关系 他们听过更糟的脏话
That's all right. They hear worse.
那是肯定的
Yeah, no doubt.
要加冰吗
So, you want ice in yours?
不要 哥们儿 那不是十块钱以下的便宜酒
No, man, that's a double-digit vino.
连瓶塞都是软木的呢
Even has a cork.
赞
Swell.
这活页封面不俗啊
I like your binders.
- 谢谢 - McNulty给我们的
- Thanks! - McNulty gave them to us.
- 你们叫他McNulty? - 是啊
- McNulty?  - Yeah.
- 不叫Jimmy? - 不叫
- Not Jimmy?  - No.
那Jimmy叔叔呢? 或者Jim?
Uncle Jimmy? Jim?
- 不 - 不
- No.  - No:
爹地? 老爹?
Daddy? Pops?
就叫McNulty
McNulty.
就只是McNulty
Oh, just plain McNulty.
如果我拿他那不够劲儿的货
And if I take his weak-ass product,
意味着我会少赚钱 你懂我意思不?
that means I'll be makin' less money,  you know what I'm sayin'?
我能给这地盘带来生机的唯一原因
Only reason I could bring any life  to this strip
是因为你们曾经给我的那些好货色
is because of the good shit  that y'all was givin' me.
我站这儿像个丫挺的 拿着本查尔斯·狄更斯的小说
then I'm standing here like a asshole  holding my Charles Dickens
皆因我没有小弟也没有后援
'cause I ain't got no muscle, no backup.
靠 哥们儿 这如果是在以往的时候
Shit, man. Yo, if this was the old days?
那是啊 说到以往的时候
Yeah, now, well, the thing  about the old days,
那都已经是以往了
they the old days.
现在那些跟我合作的人...
People I'm working with now...
如果你为了地产商想跟Marlo对着干
So you want to bump with Marlo  over real estate?
你自己搞定
You're on your own.
但如果你想听下我的建议
But if you want my advice--
我不需要 不用听
I don't, man. I don't.
Bodie 喂 Bodie
Bodie. Yo, Bodie.
至于我 Winchester家园区的所有小团伙 都不从我这儿批发了
Me: I lost the wholesale to every crew  in Winchester homes.
那帮人现在在进Marlor的货
Them horses takin' Marlo's shit now.
他还把独立经营的人都赶到边儿去了
He pushin' the independents  over hilltop, too.
这个月我没了三个团伙的订单
I lost three crews there this month.
东区的情况呢?
What about the East Side?
那边麻烦更严重
There we got a much bigger problem:
那些戴扬基帽的娘娘腔屌人 把本地的都赶跑了
all those ugly-ass bitches in Yankee  hats chasin' all the locals away.
我听说他们纽约人踢走了大部分Delroy的人
I heard them New York boys ran off  most of Delroy's people,
那些留下来的人都得用他们的货
and those that stay gotta  take they package.
所有这些理论都是只讲货是怎么来的
Man, all this theorizing about  how it be product,
不讲划分地盘么?
not territory?
你没法跟一个黑鬼讲这些大道理 如果抢走了全部的地盘
You can't talk that shit if a nigga  snatchin' all of the territory
还一点都不进你的产品
an' won't take none of your product.
事实上Marlo只是抢走了一小部份
See, the thing is Marlo's  only takin' a little bite.
他们那些纽约小猫就像沃尔玛开到镇里一样
Them New York cats is like Wal-Mart  comin' to town.
我看 是时候让沃尔玛回老家去了
Me, personally, I think it's time  Wal-Mart went home.
如果我们要跟他们斗 我们得全部一起上
If we gonna bump with 'em,  it's got to be all of us.
要我说啊 我倒是希望跟Marlo一起来对付他们
I tell you what: I'd like to see Marlo  with us in on that one.
你们懂我意思? 一个大巴尔的摩团队
You know what I mean?  One big Baltimore team.
Marlo能让一个不顺眼的黑鬼消失 对不对?
Yeah, Marlo can make an inconvenient  nigga disappear, can't he?
我听说他跟西港的殡仪馆扯上了某种联系
I heard he got some kinda hookup  at this funeral home in Westport.
棺材进去的时候需要两个护柩人来抬
Coffin goes in there needs two pallbearers.
出来的时候则需要8个人来抬那鸟东西 你们懂我意思吗?
Come out, you need eight to carry  that bitch, you know what I mean?
不 不  他是用他们来让那些排屋的人闭嘴
Nah nah. He usin' them shut-up rowhouses.
扔个尸体在那里面 没人能分得清 这个或那个的味道
Dump a body in there, no one  can tell one smell from another.
不管他在做什么 他冷血 但不是傻瓜
Well, whatever he doin', he cold,  but he ain't stupid.
我想是时候尝试跟那小子谈一谈了
Think it's time to try again  to talk to the boy.
我希望你能说些比Stringer更有说服力的话来
I hope you got better shit  to say than Stringer
因为那年轻人至今还没听过谁的说辞
'cause young'un ain't  given no one an ear yet.
靠 Jimmy 你现在整个一宅人了啊
Dang, Jimmy,  you're a domesticated motherfucker.
我想我是的
Yeah, I guess I am.
我们还好了
Yeah, we're good.
港口现在怎么样了
How's everything at the port?
- 没动静 - 现在到处都没动静
- Quiet.  - It's quiet everywhere.
- 连西部也是 - 可不
- Even the Western.  - Yeah.
我感觉很不舒服 事情不对劲
I'm having a hard time with it,  though. Somethin' ain't right.
趁还没变化前享受享受吧
Well, enjoy it while it lasts.
- 你手上有什么在做的么? - 我拿到一个案子
- You working something?  - Yeah, I got this one case.
我知道枪手是谁 但我找不着他
I know who the shooter  is but can't find him.
他会出现的
He'll turn up.
可能吧
Maybe.
还要吗
More?
天呐 不用了
Oh, mercy. No, ma'am.
甜点?
Dessert:
我想着不如到外面去吃甜点
I was thinking we might  go out for a little taste.
除非你要哄小孩上床睡觉
Unless you got to tuck in the kids.
我不知道
I don't know.
没关系 Jimmy 你去吧 我带他们去睡
Oh, it's fine, Jimmy. You go.  I'll tuck 'em in.
- 她信任你 - 是啊
- She trusts you. - Yeah.
晚饭前非得来个案子处理一下不可哈
Can't go to dinner  without catching a page, huh?
什么状况
What now?
嫖客去洗澡时候 她翻他的钱包
Her john jumps in the shower.  She rummages his wallet.
他发现了
He figures it out
揍她揍到隔壁房打电话给前台
and beats on her till the people  next door call the front desk.
先生 如果你的钱不在她身上
Sir, if she doesn't have the money on her
我不知道有什么我可以做的
I don't know what I can do.
你殴打里面那个女人了吗
Did you beat that woman in there?
我只是想要拿回我的钱
I just want my money back.
抱歉 Gergen先生 我得跟我的保安总管说点事
Excuse me, Mr. Gergen. I need a moment  with my director of security.
如果她提出起诉 我要把那个混帐东西铐起来
If she presses charges,  I'm cuffin' that motherfucker.
Colvin先生 这是一起微妙的事件
Mr. Colvin, this is a delicate matter.
微妙个屁
"Delicate"? Shit.
Gergen先生是一家全国性的 会议主办人机构的代表
Mr. Gergen represents a national  consortium of convention planners,
他一直是我们酒店的朋友
and he's been a friend of the hotel--
Colvin先生 Colvin先生
Mr. Colvin: Mr. Colvin:
你拿了他的钱 而他痛打了你一顿是吧
Now, you took his cash  and he beat you good, huh?
他为了多少钱打你
How much he beat you for?
多少钱?
How much?
把手铐给我
Give me the cuffs.
不 Colvin先生 我--
No, Mr. Colvin. I...
这是搞什么呢
What the fuck is this?
她偷了我的钱 而你却要把我关起来么
She steals my money,  and you're gonna lock me up?
你会被控侵犯人身罪
You're gettin' charged with assault.
你要是控告她偷窃的话 我也会给她上铐的
You wanna charge her with the theft,  I'll put the cuffs on her, too.
但你会去坐牢 鸟人
But you in a wagon, shitbird.
Colvin先生 这样做是不行的
Mr. Colvin, this is not acceptable.
不 他得去坐牢
No. He's goin' in a wagon.
Colvin先生 我不得不坚持我的立场
Mr. Colvin, I have to insist.
做了30年的警察 我从没给一个应受指控的人摘过铐子
30 years a police officer,  I never took cuffs off a right charge.
也没打算这会儿来开这个先例
Ain't about to start now.
你不是一名警察 Colvin先生
You're not a police officer, Mr. Colvin.
你在为我们酒店工作
You work for us.
不了 我够了
Naw, I'm good.
你宝贝着那点酒养金鱼啊
You nursin' that thing like a baby bird.
你知道在贫民区的那些小街角里
You know those little corner joints  in the ghetto
他们卖三文治 炸鸡 湖鳟鱼
that sell subs,  and fried chicken, lake trout?
湖鳟鱼?
Lake trout:
就像纽约的鸡蛋奶油
Like egg creams in New York.
- 没鸡蛋 就没奶油 - 正是
- No eggs, no cream. - Exactly.
没有湖 就没有鳟鱼
No lake, no trout.
它们是步鱼 白鱼 杂鱼
They're pogies. Whitefish, trash fish.
没错 白杂鱼
Exactly. White trash fish.
湖鳟鱼这个词 完全就是市场营销
I mean, "lake trout." That's all marketing.
它完全被包装成它本不是的某种东西
It's just all dressed up  like something it ain't.
你知道我在说什么吗
You know what I'm sayin'?
有的时候事物就是事物本身
Sometimes it is what it is.
真的就是这样的
It really is.
真深奥
That's deep.
- 我喜欢你的思维方式 - 彼此彼此
- I like the way you think. - Yeah, you too.
等等
Hold on.
该死 Bug 如果你会系一根鞋带 就会系另一根
Dang, Bug, if you can tie one shoe,  you can tie the other one.
听见了吗
You hear me?
满脸饼干屑
Cookies all on your face.
走吧
Come on.
好啊 矮子 开学第一天做好准备了?
What up, shorty? Ready for the first day?
是呀 他等不及想升三年级了
Yeah, he can't wait to be in the third grade.
是吧 Bug
Ain't that right, Bug?
嘿
'Sup?
Dukie
Dukie.
酷
Cool.
瞧你们这帮了不起的8年级生
Look at all these big-ass eighth graders  out here.
看着像些准备挨揍的6年级生
Look like some sixth-graders  gonna get banked.
来 进来 我有些东西给你们看
Yo, come in here.  I wanna show y'all somethin'.
进去吧 Bug
Go ahead, Bug.
你好吗 小孩 你的运动衫太夸张了 孩子
Yo, what up, boy?  That jersey's crazy, son.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where you get that at?
你看这个
Yo, check it.
跟我爸一起在餐馆的一位仁兄画了这些画
This dude in the joint  with my father drew these.
我打算弄一个在我手臂上
I'm about to get one on my arm.
这是你么 为什么你要把你自己画在你的手臂上
Is this you? Why would you  get yourself on your arm?
难道为了以防万一你忘记了自己长什么样?
In case you forget what you look like?
这些是什么意思 哥们儿
Yo, what do these mean, man?
哦 这个意思是心 他很有心的心
A'ight, this one means "heart"-- like, you know, "He got heart"--
那个意思是狮子 （明明是虎...）
and that means "lion."
你怎么知道的
How you know that?
那家伙可能在耍你 比如说这个字
Word, the dude could be playing you.  Like, this one,
说不定意思不是心 而是婊子
instead of "heart,"  it could mean like "bitch"
或者别的什么 而这一个
or something. And like this one,
有可能意思是小逼或者小丑
it could mean like "pussy" or "clown."
少来了 操你们这帮直娘贼
Come on, man. Fuck y'all motherfuckers.
- 它们也有可能是这个意思呢 - 臭小子 给我滚出去吧
- They probably do, too.  - Man, get outta my house.
你们得先对我这人有个大致了解
Understand something about me:
我肩章上的这些杠杠
I may be wearing these bars,
都是凭我的真本事得来的
but I worked the bricks to earn 'em,
我是个货真价实的警察 由始至终 一贯如此
and I am stone-cold police first,  last, and always.
冬天我顶风冒雪
Froze my balls off in the winter,
夏天我汗流浃背 跑上 跳下
sweated 'em in the summer, ran, jumped,
跌打滚爬跟坏人搏斗 一年到头 风雨无阻 从不间断
rolled in the dirt  with the bad guys 24/7/365.
我对这个组怀有崇高的敬意
Now, I'm a great admirer of this unit.
Avon Barksdale
Avon Barksdale?
是你们所捕获的一头大猎物
That was a 14-point buck you bagged.
然而 我们要做到更好
However, we are gonna do better.
如果有什么案子要办
And if there's a case to be made out there,
我们一起办
we'll make it together
投入我们的优质工作和优质管理
with good work and good supervision  of that work.
你们办案进程的每一步都要向我汇报
I want to be briefed every step  of the way.
有问题吗
Questions?
没问题
No?
很好
Good.
哎 你分到谁的班里去了
Yo, who you got?
我分到--
I got...
- "Prez"-- - "Prez"什么啊
- "Prez"--  - "Prez"-- what?
我分到Scott太太那个班
I got Mrs. Scott.
妈的恨透那个臭女人了
Fuckin' hate that foul bitch, man.
她也没那么坏了 至少你没给分到Sampson那个班
Man, she ain't that bad.  At least you ain't got Sampson.
这倒也是
Yeah, I know.
Michael 谁是你的老师?
Yo, Michael, who you got?
看...
Look...
好象是叫"Presborowski"? "Prez"--
"Presborowski"? "Prez"--
他是新来的白人 我们可以给他起个名字嘛
Yo, he new and white. We got it made.
这是怎么了
Uh-oh, look at this.
怎么没见公家车送你回来?
Where is your fine take-home car?
我自己送自己回来了
Got took home.
我们得谈一谈
We need to talk.
6年级在一楼
Sixth grade is on the first floor!
7年级在二楼
Seventh grade is on the second.
8年级的家课室在三楼
Eighth-grade homeroom is on the third floor!
不要走下楼的楼梯
Don't go up the down staircase.
大家保持快而静
Quickly and quietly, people.
我看着你呢 Quantell
I see you, Quantell.
我也看见你了
I see you too.
就要开始上课了 快点
School's getting ready to start. Come on.
亲爱的 见你回来真好
Hi, dear. Good to see you back.
怎么样了 Turner 你又回来受罪了啊
Yo, what up, Turner. You back for more?
我靠 我爱死开学第一天了 小子
Aw, damn, man. I love the first day, son.
人人都搞那么友好
Everybody all friendly an' shit.
Namond Brice 我们这就要开始管教你了么
Namond Brice. Already, we're starting?
我靠
Damn, man.
再让我看见 我就要没收它们了
Next time, they stay in my drawer.
你说了算 姐们儿
Yo, whatever, man.
真没劲 这么快就蔫了 小子
I know, right? Already, son.
可不是嘛
I know, right?
靠 这些小屁孩真疯狂
Damn, these kids are crazy and so.
可不嘛 我们是7年级生了
Yeah. We're seventh graders.
哎 Dang 你瞧见Neesy没
Yo, dang. You see Neesy?
嘿 他们几个厮都把耳机戴上了 爽啊
Yo, them bitches is on steroids, word.
真爽
Word, son.
要是把那几个贱人送到伊拉克
Send them bitches to lran.
那玩意儿肯定立马死翘翘
That shit'd be over in a heartbeat.
看下这个表 按排的位置位
Okay, check the chart to see  where you're sitting.
看下座位表
Check the chart.
你好 我是Randy
Hi, I'm Randy.
Randy 你好
How are you doing, Randy?
看下座位表
Check the chart.
好了 早上好
Okay. Good morning.
Okay, good morning.
听着 闭嘴
Yo! Shut up!
早上好
Good morning.
我是你们专用教室的老师 显然的
I'm your homeroom teacher, obviously.
我的名字是Pryzbylewski先生
My name is Mr. Pryzbylewski.
不过你们可以叫我 Pryzbylewski先生
But you can call me Mr. Pryzbylewski.
好的 让我们来认识一下大家
Okay. Let's find out who you are.
这是Donnelly太太在讲话
This is Mrs. Donnelly.
各位老师 我们的第一声铃出了故障
Teachers, we had trouble with first bells,
因此一分钟后你们将听到换教室的铃响
so expect the class change  to ring in one minute.
请学生们步行 不准跑
Students will walk, not run,
有秩序地到下一个课室
to classes in an orderly manner.
好吧 嗯 我们就
Okay, um, we'll, uh,
迟一点再互相认识吧
get to know each other a little later.
抱歉 借光 借光
Sorry. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Latifah
Latifah.
对不起
Uh, sorry.
我的公车卡哪去了
Where my bus passes at?
Crystal Judkins 你没在名单上
Crystal Judkins, you're not listed.
Crystal 你看我像Crystal吗
Crystal? I look like Crystal to you?
我是Charlene
I'm Charlene.
Ronald Parker
Ronald Parker:
我是Karim Williams Ronald在那边呢
Ha. Karim Williams. Ronald over there.
天哪
Aw Jeez.
哎 Prez先生 我要用通道卡去上厕所  紧急状况
Yo, Mr. Prez, I need a hall pass  for the bathroom. It's an emergency.
各位同学 我要收回所有的公车卡
Everyone, I need those bus passes back.
别动 每个人都呆在原位不要动
Hold on. Whoa. Everyone,  stay where you are.
呆那儿别动 我要收回那些卡
Stay where-- I need those passes back.
紧急状况 Prez先生
It's an emergency. Mr. Prez...
各位 我要收回所有的公车卡
Everyone, I need those bus passes back.
那些需要卡的孩子...
The kids that need them...
- Prez先生 - 什么事
- Mr. Prez...  - What?
自己去拿一张好了
Just take one.
- 我要收回所有的公车卡 - 这个课室里的所有人都不准离开
- I need those bus passes back! - No one leaves this room
直到Pryzbylewski先生 把所有的公车卡收回去
until Mr. Pryzbylewski  gets those bus passes back.
还要我再说一遍么
Do I need to say that twice?
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢
???
你很快就能自己搞定了
You'll get the hang of it.
进来
Come in.
你到底要不要进来
Are you coming in or what?
我这就进来了
I'm coming in, okay?
您要见我吗 长官
You asked to see me, sir?
是的
I did.
面见是我深入了解手下人的方式
Seeing as how I like to know  my boys in depth:
你为什么想加入这个部门?
why'd you want this unit?
实话实说么
Honestly?
我参加了警司考试 成绩挺高的
I took the sergeant's test,  scored pretty high,
但还没够格 Hoskins警督跟我
but not high enough.  And Lieutenant Hoskins,
我们一直一起上课来着
we went through the academy together.
他说这个部门 是我向上爬的一个好起点
He said that this-- this is a good detail  for going up the ladder.
我知道我不得不捱上一段时间
I mean I know you have to do it  for a while,
但也许明年 如果我在这儿表现好的话
but maybe next year,  if I do good here,
他们会把我提上去
they'll reach down for me.
明年哈
Next year, huh?
对于某些事情来讲 等上一年算是很久的了
I mean, for some things,  that's a long time to wait.
什么意思
Excuse me:
我听说你是个好警察
I hear you're a good cop.
我还听说你分得清谁是你的朋友
I also hear you recognize  who your friends are
并且对他们忠心不二
and that you're loyal to them.
我没有听错吧
Did I hear all that right?
绝对没错
Absolutely.
你在排名表上排第几
Where are you on the list?
他们只录取15个人 但是
They took 15, but--
30几啊  我还以为你要告诉我你排在至少60名以后
Thirt-- man, I thought you  were gonna say something like 60,
或者 95名什么的
or, you know, 95.
等等 我打个电话给我的人Burrell
Hey, let me call my man Burrell.
没必要浪费一个像你这样的好警察 陪着政客们开车瞎转悠
No need in wasting good police  like you chauffeuring around politicians.
我都不知该说什么好了 市长先生
I don't even know what to say, Mr. Mayor.
这太出乎意料了
This-- this is unexpected.
不足挂齿
Don't mention it.
今天是第一天 我们来搞点气氛
Today being the first day,  let's have some fun.
我会给你们出些数学谜题
I'm gonna throw you a little math puzzle,
看能不能让你们开动脑筋想问题
see if I can get you thinking on your feet.
Andre正要离开巴尔的摩
Andre is leaving Baltimore...
Prezbo先生 我要换个座位
Uh, Mr. Prezbo,  I need to change my seat
我旁边这男生臭得跟垃圾箱似的
'cause this boy here smells  like a garbage can.
你需要学会多体谅一下别人
All right, you need to work a little  on your compassion skills.
得了吧 是他需要学会该如何使用肥皂和水
Yeah, he needs to work a little  on his soap and water skills.
好了 正如我所说的
All right, like I was saying,
我的朋友Andre正要离开巴尔的摩
uh, my friend Andre is leaving Baltimore.
他以每小时60英里的速度
He's going 60 miles an hour--
巴尔的摩的那一区啊 东区还是西区
Hey, what side of Baltimore, east or west?
哪个区都无所谓
It doesn't make any difference.
那是你的想法
That's what you think.
好吧 东区
Okay, east.
西区 西区 好了吧
West, west, okay?
就这样
Okay.
他呢 正在去往费城
Uh, and he's going, uh, to Philadelphia...
老兄 费城人是狗屁
Man, Philly's ass.
喂 你认为Allen lverson是狗屁么
Yo, you think Allen lverson is ass?
- 好了 打住 - 他只是为费城人演戏 他不是那儿的人
- Okay, stop.  - He only play for them. He ain't from there.
我可不会为六年级生演戏 不管他们付我多少钱
Hey, I never play for the Sixers  no matter how much they pay me.
黑鬼 他们会付钱让你滚蛋 哈哈
Nigga, they'd pay yo' ass to go away. Ha ha.
够了
Enough!
好了 Andre正在离开巴尔的摩  巴尔的摩西区
Okay, Andre's leaving Baltimore,  West Baltimore,
以每小时60英里的速度前往费城
traveling 60 miles per hour.  He's going to Philadelphia
也就是80英里以外
which is 80 miles away.
他开的是什么车
What kind of car?
哎 他走的是95号公路 他得小心别让警察抓到他超速
Hey, he drivin' on l-95,  he need to watch out for the state police.
他们专门针对黑人的
They be profilin' niggas.
他可没说Andre是黑人啊
He ain't say Andre was black, yo.
得了吧 Randy 这人名叫Andre 又来自西区哦
C'mon, Randy. "Andre"? From the West Side?
- 喂 他可没说他是黑人 - 你明知道他就是黑人
- Hey, he ain't say he was black.  - Yo, you know he black.
行了 行了 我说行了
Okay. Okay. I said okay!
Prezbo先生 你说他是开车旅行的
Mr. Prezbo. You say he travelin' in a car.
是他在开车么 还是说他坐在车后座呢
Is he driving?  Or is he like in the back seat?
好了 大家听我说 开心就是开心
All right, you know what? Fun is fun--
坐到座位上去
Take your seats!
每个人都坐下
Everybody sit down!
哎
Hey.
这儿一切都还好么
Everything okay in here?
为什么Massey警官没在
Why isn't Officer Massey present?
她在窃听线上守了一通宵呢
Working overnight on the wire.
出席所有的警员会议 现在属于强制性任务 通知她
Attendance at all office meetings  is now mandatory. Inform her.
对这个Marlo Stanfield
And this Marlo Stanfield?
- 我们最多就只能做到这样么 - 长官
- This is the best we can do? - Sir?
就是这个家伙  让我们浪费了数个月的时间用窃听装置追踪他么
This is the guy we're wasting months  chasing with a wiretap?
用这时间我们完全可以在外面实地 做十几种其他不同的事情了
We could be on the street  doing a dozen other different things.
Stanfield是新来的
Stanfield is a comer.
他拥有很多西区的产业
He's got a lot of West Side real estate.
在他手里死了多少人
How many bodies on him?
去年他跟Barksdales的人干了一仗杀了几个人 但最近没有做什么
He fought a war against the Barksdales last year  and dropped a few, but nothing recent.
最近什么都没有
Nothing recent?
他拥有巴尔的摩西区 但是没有杀人
He owns West Baltimore  but with no bodies
这可能只是我个人的想法 但在18年的经验里
Maybe it's just me,  but in 18 years out there,
我还没见过猫儿不吃腥的
I have never seen a carnivore eat a carrot.
他沉寂了一段时间
He's been quiet for a time--
一段时间? 这个城市半截子都泡在血水里
"For a time"? This city's up  to its hips in blood
而你们却在一个 只有前科的家伙身上浪费时间?
and you are sitting on one guy  with a history?
你们需要按新秩序办事了
Okay, here's the new world order, guys.
我要好的 见效快的货色
I want good, quick rips.
每个月有6个 10个 20个重案
Six, 10, 12 felony cases a month.
也就是说不再搞什么长线窃听装置 不再搞传讯
That means no more long-ass wiretaps,  no more subpoenas,
不再在屁事儿上扭扭捏捏
no more mincing around on shit.
我们的人要到外面实地工作 然后带着统计资料回来汇报
We get out on the street  and come back with stats.
Barksdaler的案子撤掉
The Barksdale case is closed,
Stanfield的窃听线再运作30天后
and when the Stanfield wire comes up  for another 30 days,
我们也要撤案了
we close out on that as well.
- 明白了吗 - 见鬼去吧
- Understood? - You know, to hell with this.
我们搭上了窃听装置 要由法官来决定什么时候撤销掉
We got a wiretap up, and a judge  decides when it comes down.
这个嘛 警探
Well, Detective,
副总警监会跟你谈这个的
the Deputy Ops is gonna talk  to you about that.
B桌 把那些卡片收起来
Table B. Put those cards away.
Kareem Myers 坐下来
Kareem Myers. Sit down.
哎 哎 听着 听着
Yo, yo, listen, listen.
奇巧脆心巧克力一元 史力克巧克力糖一元
Kit Kats' $1, Snicker bar's $1,
大头糖一元 扭条糖一元
Warheads' $1, Twizzlers' $1.
酸软糖50分 香口胶50分
Man, Sour Patch 50c, and gum 50c.
你们能在商店里买到的东西 我都能给你们弄到这儿来
Anything you can get at the store,  I can get in here for y'all.
小熊橡皮糖 没问题 我有士力架和M&M巧克力
Gummy bears? Ain't a problem.  I got Snickers, M&Ms.
哎 看看这价钱 便宜到笑啦
Yo, check this price and come holla at me.
哎 买二得三的折扣价哦
Yo, I'm runnin' a three-for-two discount,
谁要订明天的货可以跟我下单喽
and I'm taking personal orders  for tomorrow...
我明天会来的
I'll be here tomorrow.
如果你们想要什么特别的东西 就来跟我说一声喽
...so if you want something special,  just come holla at me.
这就是啦 哥们儿
There it is, yo.
这是怎么回事 怎么不给我一支水枪算了
Why not give me a water pistol?
听着 Renaldo 你只要依计行事就可以了
Hey, yo, Renaldo, you just remember  about how we gonna do.
准能成的
It'll play.
喂 胖子 那个包裹
Oye, Gordo. The package.
赶紧的 混蛋
Avanza, cabron!
就凭你手上那个破烂玩意儿么 黑鬼 你发神经啊
With that raggedy-ass piece?  Nigga, is you crazy?
失心疯了吧 难道你不知道这东西是防弹的么
Loco or something? Don't you know  the shit is bulletproof?
你不明白
You don't understand--
你听到这孩子说的话了
You heard what the boy said.
还要一盒纽堡烟
An' a box of Newports.
还没找我钱呢
Where my change, yo?
别对我瞪眼
Don't wild me.
你看到他那张丑脸上的表情么
Hey, yo, you see the look on his mug?
就为了这我们每天才有奋斗的目标
That's the reason  why we get up every morning.
好了 好了 好了
Okay! Okay okay.
假设
Now,
Andre的朋友Yvonne
Andre's friend Yvonne
计划跟他在费城见面
is supposed to meet him in Philadelphia.
好啊 Andre要上那个贱人了
Yeah. Andre gonna bone that skank.
请你闭嘴行不 Prezbo先生想要教给我们一些知识呢
Can you please shut up? Mr. Prezbo  is tryin' to teach us somethin'.
你才该闭嘴呢 婊子 他什么也没得教给我
You shut up, bitch.  He ain't teachin' me nothin'.
但是Yvonne呢 是从纽约过来的
Yvonne, though, is coming from New York.
因此我想问你们的问题是
So my question for you is--
第一 谁先到达费城?
A, who arrived in Philly first,
Andre还是Yvonne?
Andre or Yvonne?
第二 快多少时间?
And B, by how much time?
第三--
And C...
谁鸟我呢?
who gives a rat's ass?
有了这笔基金 选举委员会不但会 重新考虑我们该如何利用本院资源
With this grant, the mandate is not only  to rethink the way we utilize institutions,
更会帮助我们将职责扩大到不再单纯依赖于
but to help us start getting  past having to rely on jail
监狱和戒瘾场所的范畴
and drug rehab as our only responses.
我们要找一个特殊的目标群体进行预防注射
We're looking for a specific  target group to inoculate,
这是从流行病学的角度来讲的
epidemiologically speaking...
医生 抱歉 我不是学者
Doctor, um, pardon me,  I'm not an academic.
八杆子都打不着的
Not by a long shot.
你到底 到底是在说些什么啊
But, what exactly are you--  are you saying here?
他是说他有很多钱 可以提出一些方案
He's sayin' he's got a lot of money  to come up with some way
打击那些在街角做生意的小子们
to go at those boys out there  bangin' on the corners.
我说的就是这个意思 没错
That's what I mean, yes.
那我在这里面能起什么作用呢
So where do I come in?
薪水方面如果大家合适的话
Well, if the salary arrangements  are suitable,
你的职责将会是作为一名实地调查人员
your duties would be to perform  as a field researcher,
作为一名在城市环境里操作的联络员
a liaison operating in the,  uh, urban environment.
你扮成混混到外面去 找个街角的小子来 让他去折腾
You go out in the 'hood and get him  some corner boys to mess with.
瞧 这就是为什么我需要 一个像你这样的人跟我配对儿
See? This is why I need somebody  like you to be paired up with me.
我一人到外面去的话--
I go out there on my own--
他们早把你大卸八块卖钱分了
And they sell your tenured ass for parts.
的确如此
In so many words.
不说我了 唔 我们要找的人 年龄在18至21岁之间
Anyway, um, we're looking for  18- to 21-year-olds.
从人口统计上看 这个年龄段是犯罪行为的高峰期
This is where we see the demographic peak  in violent behavior.
能让我们单独说几句话么
You excuse us for a minute?
如果没你在旁边作翻译的话会出什么状况
What happens when you ain't  around to translate?
别跟我扮无知 Bunny
Don't play ignorant on me, Bunny.
你跟这些人完全可以周旋自如
You can back-and-forth  with any of these guys.
我是见过你做事的
I've seen you work.
另外 很明显你不适合为私企打工
Besides, it's clear you ain't cut  out for the private sector.
18至21岁
18 to 21?
到那个年龄 他们已经深陷泥潭 他是白费力气
By that age, they're deep in the game.  He's fucked on that.
那你就证明给他看嘛
So show him.
5万年薪
50,000,
80/20医疗保险计划 公司配给自用车
80-20 health plan and a take-home vehicle.
他们能给3万我就已经为你偷笑了
I'd be amazed if they give you 30,
外加最便宜的医疗保险和公车月票
an HMO and a bus pass.
好吧 我们走
All right.Let's go.
(课堂算术例题的正确答案)
操蛋Prezbo
保重 回见
Peace. See you later.
如果我现在走进去 你知道会让我变成什么样的人么
I go in there now, you know  what that makes me?
执掌办公室的屌毛政客
Some fucking asshole politician  who's running for office.
Watkins的车 他是第40区的州参议员
Watkins. 40th District.
你通知记者了么
You call the reporters?
三个频道全都通知了 还有太阳社的人
All three channels and "The Sun."
请接受我的吊慰
My condolences.
- 我是Thomas - 我知道你是谁
- I'm Thomas-- - I know who you are.
有心了
Thanks for your respects.
对您失去至爱我深感痛惜
I'm so sorry for your loss.
我们本不该出席今天这样的场合 只因为
We shouldn't be here today just because ...
您的儿子作为证人挺身而出
your son came forward as a witness.
你说的是什么意思
What do you mean?
我知道这--
I know it's...
我只是为您的所失感到惋惜 仅此而已
I'm just sorry for your loss. That's all.
对家长来说这是最恐怖的恶梦
A parent's worst nightmare.
我不知道在这种事发生后 谁还能继续生活下去
I don't know how anybody  can go on after this.
是啊 我也无法想像
Yeah, me neither.
- Daniels小姐 - 议员
- Ms. Daniels. - Councilman.
11区的竞选形势如何?
How's things going over in the 11th District?
比我所指望的要更困难
Harder than I'd hoped for.
市长的投票也帮不上太大的忙
Even on the mayor's ticket.
是啊 Eunetta建立的根基颇为牢固
Yeah. Eunetta's pretty well entrenched.
不过还是要祝你好运
Good luck with it, though.
议会是肯定能用得上你的
The council sure could use you.
Carcetti议员 您能给我们说两句么
Councilman Carcetti,  can you give us a minute?
议员 这边
Councilman, over here.
各位请听我说 我很抱歉
Look, guys, I'm sorry, you know.
现在不是时候
Now's not the time.
我没有什么可说的 抱歉
I don't really have anything to say.  I'm sorry.
- 什么呀 他在开什么玩笑 - 他叫我们来这儿做什么啊
- What, is he kidding? - What did we come out here for?
你不想要媒体覆盖报道么 你脑子有毛病吗
You don't want the press coverage?  Are you out of your mind?
我们可以在11点的报道里出场 只限于电视报道
We'll get time on the 11 :00  from the visual alone.
但要我在这个地方做演讲 在这个节骨眼上
But I start making speeches right here?  Now?
别人会怎么看我呢
How's that really gonna look?
老板 在政治舞台上 你这个借口也太他妈蹩脚了
Boss, as political theater,  this is pretty fucking lame.
你知道 这要看观众是怎么想的
Yeah, well, you know, that depends  on the audience.
这是Shawn Williams
This is Shawn Williams.
Mello警探 请给当值长官打电话
Lieutenant Mello,  please call shift commander.
老板 你要我留下来么
Boss, you want me to stay?
不必 我能搞定
No. We're good.
我说 Shawn
So, Shawn...
你是警察 他不是
You police. He ain't.
Shawn 你几岁
Shawn, how old are you?
18岁 你多少岁呢 你这光头王八蛋
18. How old are you,  you shinehead motherfucker?
你有个妹妹 对吧 Shawn?
You have a sister, Shawn?
你他妈的想对我妹妹动什么念头?
What the fuck you want with my sister?
还有这个他妈的长得跟芝士似的 混蛋家伙在写什么呢?
And what the fuck's this Chuck E.  Cheese-lookin' motherfucker writing?
让我们假设说你的妹妹被人侮辱了
Let's say you hear that your sister  was assaulted.
谁干了我姐姐
Oh, who fucked with my sister?
她没有 我只是说--
She wasn't. I'm just saying--
说什么说? 为什么你要耍我? 王八蛋
Sayin' what? Why you fuckin'  with my head, motherfucker?
这个贱人又在写东西了
And this bitch is writing again.
习惯而已
It's a habit.
那么如果你听说你妹妹被人殴打了 你会怎么做
Now, what would you do if you heard  your sister got beat up by some guy?
你是说哪个妹妹呢 如果是Cherise的话 那多数是她自找倒霉
Which sister? I don't know. 'Cause  it's Cherise, she probably had it coming.
好吧 那就另外一个妹妹吧
All right, another sister then.
Danielle么 我会干死那小子
- Danielle?  - I'd fuck that guy up.
我会干得他屁眼都堵掉
I'd fuck his ass shut.
可你在监狱里呀
With you in jail.
我会找我手下的人去做
I'd get my boy to do it.
要是你没有手下呢?
What if you didn't have no boy?
那等我出了监狱我会自己去找那个黑鬼
Then I'd get the nigga myself  when I get out.
要是你被判的是终身监禁怎么办?
Well, what if you had a life sentence?
那我就他妈的越狱呗
Then I'll fuckin' escape.
把那支笔给我他妈的放下来 不然我就把它捅进你屁眼里去
And put that fuckin' pen down 'fore  I shove it up your motherfuckin' ass.
要是你逃不出去怎么办呢 Shawn?
What if you couldn't escape, Shawn?
干你
Fuck you.
干死你
你会去找警察解决么?
Would you go to the police?
我就记一下这个问题
Just a question.
孩子 谢谢你保持自己的本色
Son, thanks for being you.
谢谢
Thanks.
我已经完全明白了 嗯
Look, I'm ready to acknowledge that, um,
18至21岁的小青年可能太世故了
18-to-21 might be too seasoned.
你们怎么安置少年犯的?
How you fixed for juveniles?
目前么 给他们洗脑
Right now? Fresh out.
送他们去做幼儿看护的车子刚刚开走
The van to baby booking just left.
你们是要找在案的小孩呢 还是只是小孩?
But are you looking for kids  in the system? Or just kids?
如果只是找小孩的话 可以去街拐角那儿找Douglass
'Cause if it's just kids, you got Douglass  right around the corner,
- 还有这星期可以去学校找 - 高中么?
- and school's in this week. - High school?
那是多少岁? 15至18 对吧?
That's what? 15 to 18, right?
是的 不过我会 呃 我会去找年纪更小些的
Yeah, but I would, uh--  I'd go younger even.
Kima 你好吗 妹子?
Kima. 'Sup, girl:
你确定么?
Are you sure?
拜托 当初是我把你从东部带出来  送你上位的
C'mon. I'm the one who took you out  of the Eastern, sent you to the show.
你不能回这儿来 在分区工作太委屈你了
You can't come back here;  you too good for a district.
我需要一个家 警督
I need a home, major.
如果你想要调动 应该往上级部门或至少是平级部门调啊
If you need to make a move,  move up or at least lateral.
到分区来是往低处走啊
But a district is you going backwards.
而且你也不必在我的手下工作
And you don't need to be  under my wing, either.
不管你到哪里去工作都会被重用的
You're gonna be valued no matter  where you land.
待我来帮你说说话
Let me talk to people.
我尤其喜欢你甩纸时所把握的时机
I especially liked the timing  for when you flew your paper.
相当精确
Shrewd.
我看没人能把我们这个组封杀掉
I couldn't see anybody shutting us down,
这可是选举期间呢
not with the elections.
哪个混蛋敢冒上头条的风险啊?
What asshole would risk the headline?
但会从内及外地整垮我们
But to gut us from the inside out...
Charlie Marimow 他就是我放的特洛依木马
Charlie Marimow. My Trojan horse.
现在 让我来猜猜看
And now, let me guess,
为了挽救你的窃听线  你打算去找Davis法官
to save your wire, you're prepared  to go to Judge Davis.
如果我没记错的话
If my memory serves,
这不是头一次副总监 觉得有必要想整死你
this isn't the first time a Deputy Ops  felt the need to bury you.
你有殉道的天分
You have a gift for martyrdom.
我只是怀疑
I wonder, though,
你的门徒们是否跟你一样热衷于十字架呢?
are your disciples as keen for the cross?
在你的最后报告中
In your final court report,
明智的话最好是告诉法官
it would be prudent to tell the judge
侦查工作走进了死胡同
the investigation hit a dead end.
我想你不会相信的 但是
I doubt you'll believe it, but...
我敬佩你的努力
I respect the effort.
你是个了不起的侦查员
You're a hell of an investigator.
在Marimow警探手下做事 对你来说是不是难度过高呢?
It would be too much to expect you  to serve under Lieutenant Marimow?
那人是个病毒
The man's a virus.
了解
Oh.
凶杀案组呢? 那里适合你吧?
Homicide, then. That's you, right?
对
Yeah.
我知道现在很难 探员
I know it's hard right now, Detective,
就当是帮我一个忙吧
but try to think of this as a favor.
- 这儿看来对路 - 没错
- This seems right.  - Yeah.
所我了解我原来的部门 现在归Marimow警探管了
So I understand my old unit's  gone to Lieutenant Marimow.
是这样的
Yes, it has.
所以那个部门是--
So that unit is--
- 是的没错 - 那太可悲了
- Yes, it is. - That's a shame.
我需要请求你照顾一下我的老部下Greggs
I need to ask if you could  take care of my girl Greggs.
她是名好警察 她需要一个家
She's a good cop looking for a home,
我认为她非常适合凶案组
and I think she'd be a natural homicide.
嗯
Hmm.
原本是有一个空位的
Well, there was an opening.
哎呀 刚巧昨晚补进人了
Oops. Just filled that last night.
也是一个从重案组逃出来的人 不过呢
Another fugitive from Major Crimes,  but...
看在警督你的份上
for you, Major?
让我看下有没有哪个人我不喜欢吧
Let me see who I don't love no more.
好的 假设有一颗火箭在飞行 速度是
Okay, so, if a rocket travels say,
每小时1,000英里 它一小时里飞行多远?
1,000 miles an hour,  how far does it go in an hour?
Darnell
Darnell.
Chiquan?
它想飞多远就多远呗 它是火箭船嘛
As far as it wants. I mean,  it's a rocket ship, right?
Randy?
- 这是个脑筋急转弯问题么? - 不是
- Is this a trick question: - Nope.
1,000英里?
1,000 miles?
押中了
On the money.
哦 Prezbo先生 我原打算这样回答的
Oh, Mr. Prezbo, I was gonna say that.
来呀 贱货 尽管嘲笑我吧
Go 'head, bitch. Laugh at me now.
怎么着 你也想要来点么?
What? You want some?
你在地上呆着吧 贱货
You on the fucking floor, bitch.
来嘲笑我吧
Laugh at me now.
- 喂! - 我不听屁话
- Hey!  - I don't hear shit.
Crystal你去办公室叫人打911 再去找个护士来
Crystal, have the office call 911,  and get the nurse.
所有人都回到座位上去
Everybody in your seats.
躺定就好 躺定就好
Just lay still. Just lay still.
一直压着伤口
Just keep putting pressure on it.
你做得很好 Chiquan 你做得很好
You're doing fine. Chiquan,  you're doing fine.
再坚持几分钟
Just hold on for a couple more minutes.
会没事的 会没事的
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
躺好 躺定下来
lie still.
你会没事的
You gonna be all right.